<library>
    <book>
        <title>The Great Gatsby</title>
        <author>F. Scott Fitzgerald</author>
        <year>1925</year>
        <summary>A novel set in the Jazz Age that tells the story of Jay Gatsby and his unrequited love for Daisy Buchanan.</summary>
    </book>
    <book>
        <title>1984</title>
        <author>George Orwell</author>
        <year>1949</year>
        <summary>A dystopian novel about totalitarian surveillance, censorship, and the dangers of absolute political power.</summary>
    </book>
    <book>
        <title>To Kill a Mockingbird</title>
        <author>Harper Lee</author>
        <year>1960</year>
        <summary>A story about racial injustice and moral growth in the Deep South, told through the eyes of a young girl named Scout Finch.</summary>
    </book>
    <book>
        <title>The Catcher in the Rye</title>
        <author>J.D. Salinger</author>
        <year>1951</year>
        <summary>Follows the life of Holden Caulfield, a teenager who struggles with alienation and identity in postwar America.</summary>
    </book>
    <book>
        <title>Pride and Prejudice</title>
        <author>Jane Austen</author>
        <year>1813</year>
        <summary>A romantic novel exploring manners, upbringing, morality, and marriage in 19th-century England.</summary>
    </book>
    <book>
        <title>Moby Dick</title>
        <author>Herman Melville</author>
        <year>1851</year>
        <summary>The quest of Captain Ahab to seek revenge on the giant white whale that bit off his leg.</summary>
    </book>
    <book>
        <title>War and Peace</title>
        <author>Leo Tolstoy</author>
        <year>1869</year>
        <summary>A sweeping narrative about Russian society during the Napoleonic wars, blending history and fiction.</summary>
    </book>
    <book>
        <title>The Hobbit</title>
        <author>J.R.R. Tolkien</author>
        <year>1937</year>
        <summary>The adventure of Bilbo Baggins, who joins a group of dwarves to reclaim their mountain home from a dragon.</summary>
    </book>
    <book>
        <title>The Lord of the Rings</title>
        <author>J.R.R. Tolkien</author>
        <year>1954</year>
        <summary>An epic fantasy trilogy about the quest to destroy the One Ring and defeat Sauron, the Dark Lord.</summary>
    </book>
    <book>
        <title>Harry Potter and the Sorcerer's Stone</title>
        <author>J.K. Rowling</author>
        <year>1997</year>
        <summary>The first book in the Harry Potter series, introducing the young wizard and his adventures at Hogwarts.</summary>
    </book>
    <book>
        <title>The Da Vinci Code</title>
        <author>Dan Brown</author>
        <year>2003</year>
        <summary>A thriller combining art, history, and conspiracy as Robert Langdon uncovers secrets hidden by the Catholic Church.</summary>
    </book>
    <book>
        <title>The Alchemist</title>
        <author>Paulo Coelho</author>
        <year>1988</year>
        <summary>A philosophical novel about a shepherd named Santiago who dreams of finding treasure in the pyramids of Egypt.</summary>
    </book>
    <book>
        <title>Brave New World</title>
        <author>Aldous Huxley</author>
        <year>1932</year>
        <summary>A dystopian story about a future society driven by technology, conditioning, and a loss of individuality.</summary>
    </book>
    <book>
        <title>The Kite Runner</title>
        <author>Khaled Hosseini</author>
        <year>2003</year>
        <summary>A story of friendship and betrayal in Afghanistan, exploring themes of guilt, redemption, and family ties.</summary>
    </book>
</library>